Alexandra Newman

253-224-8893 • Bella Vista, AR 72714 • alexandra.urrego@hotmail.com

Children and Youth Services Manager

Collection Development | Community Outreach | Bilingual

Team-oriented library professional passionate about literacy and education. Experienced with reference services and dedicated to continuous process improvement and patron support. Looking towards new opportunities to serve the community.

WORK EXPERIENCE

City of Bella Vista - Bella Vista, AR

04/2022 - present

Children and Youth Services Manager

As a member of the library management team, I am responsible for the development and management of children/youth services as well as the physical libraries. I Supervise the full-time youth services assistant and department volunteers.

- Plans and conducts preschool, regular youth, teen and family programming on weekly basis.
- Plans and conducts annual summer reading program for children/youth.
- Along with the PR coordinator, as well as the library team, develops children/youth programming segments of other large-scale library programming. Provides arrangement of vendors and guest speakers as needed for children/youth programming.
- Cultivates internal/external relationships and provides dialog with parents, community members, schools, targeted youth agencies and community members to help improve public library children/youth services.
- In the absence of the PR coordinator, is responsible for all social media, outreach, and communication to the public on all children/youth activities at the library.
- Serves as main point person in the absence of the library director and/or the adult services librarian.
- Works the circulation and information desks on rotating schedule and as needed.
- Working closely with the library cataloger, provides assistance in cataloging and maintaining the children/youth library, and serves as a backup cataloger as well as technical processor for all children/youth materials. In addition, provides the cataloger professional assistance with all children/youth library donations.

City of Bella Vista - Bella Vista, AR

04/2021 - 04/2022

Library Assistant (Youth Services)

Library Assistant for the Bella Vista Public Library. I worked under the supervision of the Children's Librarian and assisted with Children's department programming and circulation duties. I oversaw the teen advisory board, teen programs, and program development for ages 5-18.

- Acts as supervisor evenings/weekends and will open and close the library. Manages the circulation desk during evenings/weekends.
- Manages room booking system, ensuring proper procedures for evening/weekend.
- Assists patrons with reserves and new applications, retrieves patron requests from shelves.
- Trains and oversees work of evening/weekend volunteers.

Alexandra Newman 253-224-8893

• Provides patron assistance with computers, printer and general device tech support. Assists patrons with using the integrated library system catalog. Will regularly check on accuracy of patron accounts. Resolves customer service issues with patrons.

• Assists Children's librarian with teen night, TAB meetings, story times, and other programming needs.

City of Lompoc - Lompoc, CA

02/2017 - 06/2019

Library Branch Manager

Branch Library Manager for Vandenberg Village Library. I developed programming for youth and adult services and conducted outreach to area schools, military families, and community groups. I also provided reference and reader's advisory for all ages.

- Developed, implemented, and evaluated library services and policies for the reference and circulation in a manner that supported the overall goals of the library and ensured staff delivery of the highest quality service.
- Responsible for mending materials, reference, displays, tours, social media, staff and volunteer training, and day-to-day operations.
- Collaborated with colleagues on developing and improving educational programs offered by the library for all ages. Youth and family programs included arts and crafts, games, story hour, and other large public programing that promoted literacy and community involvement.
- Improved knowledge base in programming and outreach techniques for Spanish speaking adults and their families.

EDUCATION

University of Arkansas - Fayetteville, AR

Bachelor of Arts – Art History, degree expected 05/2021

San Antonio College – San Antonio, TX

Associates of Arts – Studio Art, 08/2015

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Communication
- Customer service
- MS Office
- Integrated Library Systems
- Administrative support
- Public Programming
- Outreach

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Vandenberg Base Library – Vandenberg AFB, CA

01/2017 - 07/2019

Storytime Volunteer

• Led Storytime program on a weekly basis for children ages 0-6 years old.